Hello everyone and
welcome to English Pod.
My name is Marco. Hi
everyone. My name is Catherine
and today Marco we're
talking about money.
That's right we're going
to take a look at another
lesson about money
but this time we're going
to learn a little bit more
about coins in the United States.
That's right, different coins, so different
sizes and shapes. They have different
names because they represent
different amounts of money.
So today we're going
to learn the names
of those coins and
we're also going to learn a
little bit about British
money. So let's check
out the dialogue. Help
me organize these coins?
That's a lot of money. What'd
you do? Break the piggy bank?
Yeah I'm going to go
to the bank and change it
for bills but first I have to
separate them into little piles.
Okay I'll find all the quarters and dimes
while you sort the nickels and pennies.
Great then we can add everything
up and take it to the bank.
I found some coins
that are not from here.
Oh yeah those are
from my trip to London.
I have like 90 pence but it
all won't add up to one pound.
Are you sure the bank will change
these coins for you? Hopefully.
All right we're back
so let's take a look at
some of this language
on language takeaway.
Language takeaway. So
first up Marco we have this
funny phrase, break the piggy
bank. What is a piggy bank?
That's right a piggy bank.
Now you may have seen this.
It has the shape of a little pig.
It's usually made out of plastic or ceramic
and it has a little hole at the top where
you can put in coins that just
basically save your money there.
All right so this is a pig-shaped bank
but it's a bank you keep in your room.
Mostly children have these
right? Yeah so if you want
to save your change or
you want to save some of
your coins that you have
or teach your children
about saving money then
usually they have a little
piggy bank where they
can store their money.
So when you break the
piggy bank usually these were
made of ceramics. So to
spend the money you have
to decide when it's very
very special or important
so you have to break
the entire bank and that's
when you take all the
coins you've been saving.
Exactly because they
didn't really have a
a little hole where you
could take it out from.
So when you wanted to take your money out
you literally had to break it. Break it.
All right so that's the piggy bank but
what do we store inside a piggy bank?
We don't store bills do we?
That's right no we sort of
coins so this is an interesting
word bill you know like the
name Bill, Bill Clinton for example.
Bills are the paper
money that we use.
All right but not capitalized
like a name because
this is a normal common
noun. Bills represent all
paper money so I could
get I could ask for change.
Could I have the change
in bills please? That's right.
And if I'm at a store
they'll give me bills maybe
a $5 bill, $10 bill. And
this also counts for
other currencies. So if
I'm in China I might get my
RMMB, my UN in bills.
So it's just a general name
for paper money. That's
right. So but what we store
in the piggy bank are
coins. Now talking specifically
about the types of
coins are the different
amounts that these
represent. Let's take a look at
those in more in detail.
All right so first up
we've got quarters.
Now this should be pretty
easy if you know your
time because a quarter is
one fourth of something.
So if we're talking about
money it's a quarter
of a dollar or 25 cents.
That's right so 25 cents
or a quarter of a dollar
or one fourth of a dollar.
We just call it a quarter.
So you know most machines or payphones
you need to insert quarters. That's right.
So you can recognize the
quarter because it's the biggest
coin and it has a
big eagle on one side.
And on the other side it
has George Washington.
George Washington that's
right. Now the next in line or
the next coin that we're going
to take a look at are dimes.
Dimes. Now these
are also recognizable
because they're the
smallest coins but that does
not mean they're
the smallest amount.
Dimes are actually the
second largest. They're 10 cents.
They're 10 cents
or 1/10 of a dollar.
And so you can say they're
10 cents or you can say dimes.
So do you have, I don't
know if you have 10
dimes that means you
got a dollar. That's right,
10 dimes equal one dollar.
And the face on the dime
is... Oh Jeffers Alexander
Hamilton. I don't know.
Now he was the first, well he created
basically the Department of the Treasury.
But Thomas Jefferson is
on another coin and that's
what we're going to look at
next. That's right, the nickel.
The nickel is like the
metal, you know, nickel.
And yeah, so this
one is a little bit
bigger than the dime but
not as big as the quarter.
Right. I think it's a
little bit thicker maybe.
It is thicker but it's
not as much money.
A nickel is five cents. Five
cents. So one 20th of a dollar.
That's right, one
20th of a dollar.
So this is what we call a nickel.
So you would call this coin.
You would say, do
you have any nickels?
Dimes and nickels usually
go together. I don't know why.
Nichols and dimes.
He's catching his nickels
and dimes means he doesn't
have very much money.
That's right. So yeah, and then on this
coin you have the face of Thomas Jefferson.
That's right. Okay. And
finally we have the only
coin that's not silver
colored. It's actually
more of a copper color.
That would be the penny.
The penny. That's right.
One cent or one penny
is the smallest of the coins. And actually
you need 100 of these to make one dollar.
That's right. So this
is very unique because
it's a different color.
It's the smallest amount.
And the face on this coin.
Do you know this one?
Yes. This one is
Abraham Lincoln. Correct.
All right. So we've got
all these important people.
All of them were
presidents actually, except for
Alexander Hamilton. That's
right. And actually I think
Alexander Hamilton looks
good better than the rest.
He was a pretty handsome. Yeah. Actually,
no, he was said to be very funny looking.
So actually, all of
these coins, you can call
them by these names and everyone
will recognize them, especially in the US.
Now, I don't really think
they apply to any other country
as we saw later on, for example,
money in England or the United Kingdom.
But usually in the US, if you say, hey, do
you have any spare change or do you have
any nickels and dimes?
Or can I borrow a penny?
Can I borrow a penny?
Actually, in the US,
they have these little
things called take a
penny to leave a penny, right?
Or give a penny, take a penny.
Yeah. You see these because pennies are
not worth very much money. And oftentimes,
people will leave a
penny. And if you have, it
may something costs 26
cents, but you only have
a quarter, you can take a
penny and then spend that.
Right. So they're
basically free pennies.
Right. You might see
in a store. And then also,
if you get change, maybe
you don't want to carry
those pennies
around or that change.
So you just leave that there.
And then you know, it's kind of
a way of recycling this
small amount of money,
which is very interesting.
It is very interesting.
But we're going to
actually take a look at
some British currency.
So let's take another
listen to the dialogue.
And when we come back, we'll explore that.
Help me organize these
coins. That's a lot of money.
What did you do?
Break the piggy bank?
Yeah, I'm going to the
bank and change it for bills.
But first, I have to separate
them into little piles.
Okay. I'll find all the quarters and dimes
while you sort the nickels and pennies.
Great. Then we can add
everything up and take it to the bank.
I found some coins that are not from here.
Oh, yeah, those are for my trip to London.
I have like 90 pence, but it
all won't add up to one pound.
Are you sure the bank will change
these coins for you? Hopefully.
All right, we're back.
So let's take a look at
these British words on
language takeaway part two.
So here we've got British
currency, the pound,
right, is the name of the
currency. So in America,
we have the dollar in
Britain. We have the pound.
Is it the sterling pound?
Yeah, pound sterling.
The pound sterling. Okay, sterling. And I
think that has to do with weight, I'm sure.
But here we've got it
divided into small and
large quantities. So where we have coins,
we might have pence. Sounds like sense.
Right, exactly. And I
think actually the penny
might come from
the British term pence.
I'm sure it does. They're
very similar and the meaning
is basically 100th of a
pound. Right, exactly.
And the pound is basically what
you would say in the US dollar.
A pound is is the
currency of England.
But actually, you know,
how in the United States,
people would say, you know,
100 bucks, yeah, which would
be a hundred dollars. Over
there, they say 100 quid.
Quid. So yeah, this is actually important
slang. In America, I would spend five bucks
at the movies. In Britain,
I would spend five quid.
And now that's a slang
term for one pound.
That's right. And actually, I've heard also
like 50p, which I think means 50 cents.
Yeah, pence.
Pence. Yeah. So 50p.
So you could say this stick of,
or this pack of gum costs 50p.
So 50p. That's right.
Half of a pound.
So as you can see, obviously,
the currencies are different,
but also it is interesting
to learn the way that
you would say it locally.
So, you know, next time,
if you're in Britain,
or you're talking to an
English person, then
you'd know if they say,
you know, 50 quid, you understand
they're talking about 50 pounds. Exactly.
So, but they don't
use the euro over there.
No, they don't
not in Great Britain.
They do use the euro on
the continent. So France, Italy.
And the euro is the name
of that currency. Okay.
All right. So a lot of
great stuff in our last
lead, although we saw
that the beginning of the
dialogue, let's talk about
what this person wants to do.
He wants to change
these coins into bills.
That's right. So the verb when you need
to exchange money is to change money.
So let's say if I go to England
and all I have is dollars,
I would say I want to
change money. Okay.
You could also say exchange,
but when we're speaking to
one another, we normally
just say change. Right.
Right. Because even
the places are sometimes
called like money changers. You know, they
say that or something like that. Exactly.
And so if I want to change
money, that means I want to maybe
change dollars for euros
or dollars for pounds.
But this also can, can
mean I want to change
change a dollar for some
quarters. Right. Right.
Because I need quarters for like
a laundry machine or telephone.
Right. And I've heard also the term is
to break. So if maybe you have a $10
bill and you need maybe a $5 bill, but you
don't have like you ask the person to break
that money. So you say,
can you break this bill?
Yeah. And that actually
makes sense because a bill
normally you break something
that's big into smaller pieces.
So if you think
about it, if I break
a glass, it becomes many
pieces. Well, if I break
a $5 bill, I want maybe
$1. I get five of those.
There's one piece and then
it breaks into many pieces.
So to break means to
ask for smaller change.
That's right. So maybe
next time you guys
need change, you can
go up to someone and say,
excuse me, can you
change this $5 bill for me?
Or can you break this
$5 bill? That's right.
All right. So a lot of interesting
language, very useful stuff.
Let's listen to the dialogue one
last time. Help me
organize these coins.
That's a lot of money. What'd
you do? Break the piggy bank?
Yeah, I'm being able to the
bank and change it for bills.
But first, I have
to separate them
into the little piles. Okay.
I'll find all the quarters
and dimes while you sort
the nickels and pennies.
Great. Then we can add
everything up and take it to the bank.
I found some coins
that are not from here.
Oh, yeah, those are
for my trip to London.
I have like 90 pence, but it
all won't add up to one pound.
Are you sure the bank will change
these coins for you? Hopefully.
All right. Coming back
to the topic now, uh,
you seem to know
a lot about this stuff.
Let's, let's test your
knowledge here on the $100 bill.
Who do we find what
president or one person?
Benjamin Franklin. That's
right. And, but he wasn't
a president, right? He was not. He was a
very important figure in American history.
Many people are familiar with
the story of Benjamin Franklin
and the kite with
the key item. Right.
And he discovered electricity.
That's right. That's right.
He was a very important
inventor and also an
important person when it
comes to the creation of America.
That's right. Now
the smaller of the bills
would be the $1 bill.
And actually now you have
a $1 coin as well. Um,
but on the $1 bill, do you
know who's on there? I
think is George Washington.
I think so. Yeah. Yeah.
So he's like the quarter
and on the $1 bill. We like
to recycle our presidents.
The $20 bill then would
be Abraham Lincoln.
Right. Oh, that's right.
So he's, they're actually on
these sort of unfair though.
Favorite presidents
in the United States.
So yeah, but they haven't
changed over time. Like in other
countries, you see that,
uh, that they change
according to, you know,
the important person
that's in government
or maybe, you know, like,
for example, in China,
you know, you have a
chairman Mao on there,
yeah, which before you did
it or in England, you have
Queen Elizabeth before
was the previous ruler, which
I think was King George VI.
So, uh, but in the
US guys flat out
100 years ago, these guys
haven't changed them since then.
Well, I think what's
America likes to
celebrate its creation, uh, which is still
a very young country, right? Right. 1776.
So it's only been what 240
years. So yeah, the idea is basically
that we celebrate the
founding, so the beginning
of the Republic. And the
men who are involved in
that, they're called the
founders, uh, George
Washington, um, James
Madison, Alexander Hamilton,
all of Brent Benjamin
Franklin, these people are
very important in
the history of America.
And that's why we
celebrate them on our money.
The one exception, of
course, is Abraham Lincoln.
He was from the
1860s as he's president.
That's right. He was, he was,
um, very important because
of the Civil War and a lot of the changes
that later happened to our constitution.
And so he's another person
who's maybe added on.
So he's basically the last guy
you guys kind of celebrate,
because you don't have, uh,
Franklin Delano, Rosa, right?
Or, uh, or, you
know, Bill Clinton or
something like that yet,
right? So I guess we gotta,
we gotta wait a while,
but that's very interesting,
the, this history aspect of currency is,
is actually very, very interesting. It is.
And one thing I like, I'd
like to add about quarters is
that in the 2000s, so
from 2000, I think on the
United States started
to make state quarters.
So you'll see oftentimes
these quarters with the
picture of a state, New
Hampshire, Maryland, Illinois,
California, and a special
symbol of that state.
And so these are special quarters from
the last maybe 10 years or so. Yeah, yeah.
I remember seeing these
because usually on the other side
of the quarter one, one side
you had George Washington.
On the other side, you had the, uh, the
eagle, the, the emblem of the flag, I guess,
not the flag, but the national
public bird or the republic.
And, uh, but now you have these states and
it says, you know, Delaware, and it has a
little, maybe, uh, I don't know, flower,
something that's represented at the state.
So that was actually very nice. It was
a collector's type thing as well, right?
People were collecting.
That's right. You can
collect all 50. Some
people did that, and I
used to see them in use.
So those are the state
quarters. And those generally are,
are newer quarters.
Okay. Interesting.
All right, guys. So we're at
a time. But if you guys have
any questions or doubts, you
could find us at EnglishPod.
com. And we'll see
you guys there. Bye.